oren.md 6/1/2023

# Oren Golan

You can download a PDF version of my resume.

I am a leader and builder of product and engineering teams. 15+ years experience envisioning, building, launching, operating, and scaling teams and products. I apply empathy in everything I do, and I am passionate about innovation, culture, and organizational development. I apply empathy in everything I do, and I am passionate about innovation, business strategy, and organizational development.



## 👤 Profile

Contact: 2121 6th Ave, #N315, Seattle, WA 98121. orengolan@gmail.com. +1 818 233 0645

- Website
- LinkedIn
- 15+ years of experience in building and leading remote engineering and product teams
- Hands-on experience with JavaScript, Node, Go, Ruby, C#, Docker, React, Svelte, and NoSQL databases
- AWS Solution Architect Associate
- Hired, coached, and scaled cross-functional, global teams
- Certified Scrum Master (with Jeff Sutherland)
- Speaking at conferences about technology, leadership, and culture
- Member and mentor in LA CTO Forum and Seattle CTO Club
- Judge at 2020, 2021, and 2022 Dempsey Startup Competitions (University of Washington)



### Experience

Software Development Manager, Amazon Video. Aug 2016 – Present, Seattle

 Led engineering team that managed a tier-1 service that powers the landing pages of all Amazon Video devices

oren.md 6/1/2023

 Reduced operational overhead by 20% by driving OKRs for Operational Excellence

- Led multiple work streams of a critical project as part of Thursday Night Football
- Conceived, developed, and launched a program that enabled Amazon engineers to go to market 2 weeks faster. Adopted by 8500 engineers with a net promoter score of 80
- Built a product flywheel that improved Amazon development tools. It led to the creation and maintenance of workshops and an onboarding tool.
- Built a community of engineers for revealing needs, finding local solutions, and generalizing them for the rest of Amazon builders community
- Led Amazon Video hackathon for US and UK teams
- Hired, mentored, and promoted software engineers
- Led hundreds of interviews as part of Amazon Bar Raiser program.
  Mentored and graduated 8 Bar Raisers

### VP of Engineering, Sanguine Biosciences. Jan 2015 – Aug 2016. Los Angeles

- Formed and mentored a new development team
- Led cloud strategy based on AWS
- Built HIPAA-compliant infrastructure for clinical research projects
- Applied lean practices for company-wide process improvements
- Implemented software development processes Scrum and Kanban
- Increased team's productivity by building CI based on Docker
- Developed highly available services and applications using Javascript, Node.js, and Golang

# Senior Software Engineer, AT&T Interactive. Jan 2012 - Oct 2014. Los Angeles

- Led a technology change for YP.com website migrating our tech stack from Ruby on Rails to a full-stack JavaScript code base (Node.js on the server)
- Won 2012 Hackathon which was to initiate YP's Engineering website
- Built a Node service that handles traffic from 10 million YP mobile apps and is responsible for push notifications
- Built a generic queuing platform that handles 500 request/sec, based on RabbitMQ, and Node.js processes

oren.md 6/1/2023

• Spoke at international conferences about client/server side technologies and software best practices

#### Ruby Developer, Borderstylo. Jul 2009 - May 2011. Los Angeles

- Built RESTful CMS Web Service + Web interface (Sinatra, MongoDB, jQuery, and Git)
- Developed 2 Rails websites using MySQL and decent test coverage with Rspec and Cucumber
- Developed mobile optimized sites using HTML5 and CSS3
- Ownership of my projects requirements, development, deployment, and maintenance
- Implemented a Kanban system for multiple teams

# Technical Project Manager and Scrum Master, MySpace. Oct 2007 - May 2009. Beverly Hills

- Accelerated the integration of an acquired start-up (kSolo) to Myspace Karaoke
- Worked with Project Managers, Architects, and 30 global Scrum teams
- Managed all aspects of Scrum: sprint planning and review, retrospectives, and Scrum of Scrums
- Measured team's velocity that helped in creating a release plan
- Increased team's velocity by implementing lean practices and tools such as Kaizen and Kanban

#### VP of Engineering,CSS LivePos. Jun 2005 - Oct 2007. San Diego

- Scaled the engineering team from 5 to 25 in San Diego and Shenzhen
- Implemented an Agile methodology (Scrum and XP)
- Hired and coached development and QA teams
- Delivered a successful SaaS product (Point of Sale software)
- Managed requirements by collaborating with clients and product owners
- Migrated legacy projects (VB6 and ASP) to modern environment (C# and ASP.NET)

## **Education and Misc**

• B.A in Computer Science - Academic college of Tel Aviv-Jaffa, Israel (Graduated: 2003)

oren.md 6/1/2023

- AWS Solution Architect Associate
- Certified Scrum Master (with Jeff Sutherland)

• Israeli Army veteran